Look, you must be joking.
Getting all big-headed just
because you got a tiny bit lucky!
Revolting and despicable!
What a self-righteous piece
of work you are!
Really, when will you feel you've had
enough of making people look foolish?
Ah, and here I am, so vehemently
and diligently appealing to you!
Just how slothful can you be?!
You're violating my rights as an
unselfish man who desires nothing but
to settle for a tiny bit of
simple, ordinary happiness!
I love you.
I'm... inside the carriage?
Emilia?
I didn't... Return by Death, did I?
She's so soft and warm.
Try not to get up to too much mischief.
Howawha?!
Emilia lost two nights of sleep
worrying about you, I suppose.
Oh, thank goodness you're
okay! And the others?
Don't worry. Everyone is
safely together, I suppose.
Man, what a huge relief! I was so worried!
Let me hug you!
Is this...
It is.
The inside of the Pleiades
Watchtower, I suppose.
You're...
Who are you?!
Are you the Sage?
I finally found you...
Master.
Master!
Oh, man! Oh, man! Oh, man!
I've been waiting so long!
Wh-Wh-What is the meaning of this?!
Hold it! Hold it! Hold it!
It's been forever! I missed you so much!
Ow!
What is this brute strength?!
Who even are you, and what is going on?!
What do you mean?! I'm Shaula!
Keeper of the Pleiades Watchtower,
and your precious student, Shaula!
There's trouble! I woke
up and Subaru was go—
Emilia-tan, help me!
Hiyah!
Wait, why?!
I don't know! I just feel very upset!
Subaru, please try not to let us down.
You're making a lewd face, Pervarusu.
I am not, and don't mash
those words together!
Master! Master!
I'll never leave you again!
Anyway! I'd like to start discussing
things before my arm gets ripped off!
We're just as baffled as you are.
This woman who barely said a word before
is hangin' all over Natsuki now.
Her?
You said it yourself, Master.
No matter what anyone asks,
don't say more than you need to!
Don't talk! Don't tell!
Hell, just stab 'em dead first!
I was just doing what you taught me!
Your master was pretty awful, huh?
Forget all that. You can
talk to everybody else, too.
Oh, man! This is awesome!
Master gave me permission!
Okay, so you are the Sage we've
heard so much about, right?
Hmm...
If it's a "Shaula" you're
looking for, yeah, that's me.
I guess my love is mutual!
But if it's a "Shaula the
Sage" you're looking for,
I dunno anything about 'em.
This is the Shaula that people
mean when they say "Shaula."
The holy gold coin has the Holy Dragon,
the gold has the first Sword Saint,
and the silver has the Sage.
She doesn't look the least
bit like this, I suppose.
Wow, that looks just like Master!
Me?! How?!
I don't think this person really
looks like Subaru, either.
Oh, I didn't recognize Master
based on his looks, so no problem!
Where exactly did you learn that phrase?
If it wasn't his looks,
how did you recognize him?
His smell!
The only person who gives
off such a nose-burningly black,
disgusting smell is Master!
I've never felt so hurt before in my life!
Seriously? Do I smell that bad?
D-Don't worry, Subaru.
I understand. Let's make sure
we have proper baths later.
You don't understand at all!
So you are Shaula,
but you aren't the Sage.
Then do the Sword Saint and Holy
Dragon sound familiar to you?
Blech!
I guess so.
Of course I've heard of them!
I've known Reid the stick swinger
and Volcanica the sarcastic forever.
They're probably doing pretty
good these days, right?
Reid has been dead for years.
For real?!
He seemed like a guy nobody
could kill! How'd he die?
Old age.
Oh, yeah.
I guess he was a human, after all.
I'll ask you straight.
Just who is your master?
That's a weird question.
You guys are traveling with
him. Shouldn't you know?
I'm sorry, but your master hit his head
on a chamber pot and forgot many things.
Really, Master? Again?
"Again"?!
All right, then, I'll make
the big announcement.
My master's name—yes, the name
of the great, renowned wise man!
The only one in this world worthy
of being known as the Sage!
We don't need a drumroll.
Tah-da!
Flügel!
Huh?
My master's name is Flügel.
Flügel the Wise Man!
Isn't that the name of the
guy who planted that tree?
Damn, that's scary! We're so high up!
And not even a handrail to
offer a sense of security!
Hey, naked lady,
this ride is way too bouncy.
A kid getting a free ride
shouldn't be so demanding.
Hey! Quit pulling my hair!
Come on, Meili. Don't antagonize her.
And no playing with her ponytail.
It's not a ponytail. It's a scorpion tail.
Huh?
Scorpion tail!
Okay, fine. Why get so hung up on that?
This door serves as the tower's
primary entrance and exit, I suppose.
Rem and Patrasche are
on the next floor up.
We have to go higher?!
Also, if this is the entrance, how did
Patrasche and the carriage get that far?
Shaula carried everything for us.
She just went, "Hup!" And lifted them up.
Pardon?
Aw, please!
That was a piece of cake!
I'm more freaked out than grateful.
Whether you're grateful or freaked out,
please just accept my
earnest feelings for you!
Smack.
You threw 'em away?!
So I guess Flügel built all this, too?
You know,
I heard he was known as the Sage,
but I never thought I'd
hear about him again here.
I don't really know what he did other
than planting that tree, I suppose.
This tower sure is huge, though.
It's finally starting to hit me now.
What's starting to hit you?
That this is the Pleiades Watchtower
that we were trying to reach.
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
If that's all you understand,
you get a 99 out of 100 at best.
That's basically a perfect score!
Well, that score factors in bonus points
for how much I love, love, love you!
Pleiades Watchtower is just a
temporary name for a temporary role.
Now that you've returned,
it'll go back to its original role.
Its original role?
Yep!
A great library where you can find
everything you ever wanted to know!
The Great Pleiades Library is so,
so, so, so happy to have you back!
Rem and Patrasche are in here?
Whoa! Ram, the vines moved!
You're too jumpy.
You'll startle the room's master.
The room's... master?
A spirit.
It feels like a jungle.
Rem...
And Patrasche.
When we rejoined Lady Emilia,
Patrasche was gravely injured.
The spirit's power has been healing her.
The spirit living here doesn't
seem to have anything like a will.
It only tries to heal the illnesses
and injuries of creatures who enter.
Then could it heal Rem?
It doesn't work on Rem.
It can't heal something that
isn't an illness or injury.
That's what the spirit decided.
So in other words, after
all this, nothing changes.
If you want to change it, you must
achieve the objective of your tower visit.
The Great Pleiades Library, huh?
I'll find the answer and get Rem back.
That goal hasn't changed.
Okay! I'm going back to the others. You?
Aren't you too worried to leave
Rem with no one watching her?
Okay, then,
I'll leave you in charge of her.
Although all I can do is watch over her...
You watching over her means plenty.
Please take care of Rem and Patrasche.
This floor is basically my den.
I spend most of my time
watching the dunes from here,
and anyone who gets close to
the tower gets shot! Shot!
I knew it.
That was you.
You have no idea what I went
through because of that.
A shot that keeps interfering
pests away from the tower:
Hell's Snipe!
Was everything all right inside?
Yeah, they're fine. Ram's watching them.
We don't know what she'll do if
she finds out you're not Flügel.
So we can't correct her
or let her know, huh?
Regulus and Petelgeuse were so much
easier to deal with than this.
Master! Somethin' wrong?
Not a thing.
I just want to make sure of one thing.
The reason you shot people
approaching the tower was...
Your orders, of course, Master!
For 400 years, I spent every single
day watching that sea of sand.
It's a story so sad, both hearing it
and telling it make me want to cry!
You were all alone for 400 years?
You'll do anything I tell you, right?
Wh-What's that serious expression for?
I won't do anything perverted.
Don't harm me or my friends.
Your master's orders were to attack
anyone approaching the tower, right?
So now that we're inside it,
there's no need to attack us.
Do not harm us. No matter what.
Okay, got it!
I've committed it to my memory as
my new orders from you, Master!
Good. That's a promise, then.
Roger that!
I'll protect you all! I'll
protect the hell out of ya!
Once again, welcome back, Master!
I, Shaula, have waited most eagerly for
the return of Flügel the Wise Man!
We've come as high as the sixth,
fifth, and fourth floors.
Above here is the exam site that takes
up the third, second, and first floors.
Exam site?
Yep. On the third floor,
you'll be tested to make sure you
qualify to enter the archive.
You have to qualify to enter the
Great Pleiades Library's archive?
That is the greatest challenge
we face at present.
I see. So the rest of you took
that exam while I was asleep.
This looks like a room I wouldn't
want to stay in very long.
I agree.
Staying long in here would rob
you of your sense of equilibrium.
A stone... slab?
One might call it the device
that sets up the puzzle for us.
When you touch that slab,
the exam will begin, I suppose.
I just need to touch this monolith?
Monolith? Somehow, that
name seems rather fitting.
I'll use that henceforth.
Here I go.
Hero vanquished by Shaula,
touch upon his grandest splendor.
What do you think?
Do you see now why we were
so surprised at first?
So what I just heard was an exam question?
Subaru, there are a few things you
must know before beginning the exam.
First, try touching the slab—rather,
the monolith closest to you.
You like the word that much?
I mean, that's fine, but...
You've returned to the starting point.
In other words, it was determined
that you failed the exam.
Naturally...
Hero vanquished by Shaula,
touch upon his grandest splendor.
I see. So I can keep trying
over and over until I pass.
That is our conjecture at present.
Just running around touching monoliths
blindly will not lead you to the answer.
That is all I can tell you.
So you guys already tried the
scattershot approach, huh?
That does seem like something
you'd try, Emilia-tan.
Still, even if you know the answer,
what do you have to do to "touch
upon his greatest splendor"?
True...
Well, you won't get anywhere standing
here thinking about it forever.
I think you should try
asking the naked lady.
I guess so.
Shaula! Can you think of any heroes
you've vanquished who fit the bill?
Only second-rates remember the
names of all the people they kill!
One as first-rate as me doesn't remember
anyone beyond the first hundred!
Yeah, I figured!
So anyway, out of the names I remember...
Let's see... Oh!
What about Reid?
Was it you who killed
the first Sword Saint?
Hey, watch it!
Th-Thanks, Big Brother.
Nah, it kinda happened because I
blurted that out without warning.
What? Does the first Sword
Saint scare you that much?
Don't be silly.
He's the progenitor of the Astrea family,
including Reinhard and his grandfather.
In addition to his sword skills, he must
have been a man of great character.
Miss Shaula, allow us to hear your
thoughts without reservation.
He was human scum.
Allow us to hear your thoughts
without reservation.
Don't pretend she never said it!
Well, at any rate, he was an awful person.
Like when a rotten little brat
grows up and still doesn't change.
He absolutely loved bullying the weak.
Hell, from his perspective, pretty
much everyone was a weakling,
so no matter who he fought,
he was bullying the weak.
He did it to me all the time.
He must've been a real monster
if he got the better of you.
Actually, wait...
There's a chance that challengers have
to defeat Shaula to enter the tower,
so the answer has to be something
I'd know without asking her.
Subaru?
Natsuki? Did ya think of somethin'?
The possibility of conquering
the tower without Shaula...
What if there's another Shaula that
Shaula doesn't realize is Shaula?
What's up, Master?
You're embarrassing me,
staring at me like that!
Beako!
That expression...
That's the expression
Betty likes to see on you!
I want to jump up high and look
at these monoliths from above.
Murak!
Just like I thought.
Did you achieve your goal, I suppose?
I sure did!
This place...
is as sadistic as they come.
I know the hero's name.
A White Sky Asterism
Natsuki, how did ya figure out the answer?
It wasn't that big a deal.
It's not you guys' fault
you couldn't solve it.
There are very few people
in this world who could.
The name of the hero
vanquished by Shaula...
was Orion.
Orion?
Wait, wait! I've never heard of any Orion!
I wouldn't expect you to.
The "Shaula" in the question
wasn't even you at all.
But I'm the only Shaula!
That's the name you gave me, Master!
I'm saying the name your master
gave you has a story behind it.
The story behind Shaula's name?
Is this another thing that
only you know, Subaru?
Well, not only me.
Where I come from,
there's a star named Shaula.
It means "stinger," but specifically,
it refers to a scorpion's tail.
A scorpion?
Legends say the hero Orion let
his ego get the better of him,
so he got stung and killed by a
scorpion that was sent to torment him,
and turned into stars.
And for its achievement, the scorpion
was also turned into a star.
They say Orion is still terrified of
that scorpion, even up in the night sky.
When you simplify it that much,
even a hero's tale sounds disappointing.
Anyway!
Groups of stars that resemble people
or animals are known as constellations.
They can also be called asterisms.
And when I looked down at the monoliths
from above... there it was.
Then, when I envisioned the
constellations and found Orion...
When you found it?
"His grandest splendor" is a tricky
way to phrase the question.
The thing is, different stars
shine in different ways.
Some are consistently bright,
while others flash brighter at times.
There are two stars in Orion that
could be said to shine the brightest.
There's Rigel,
which shines consistently...
and Betelgeuse, a variable star
that glows extra bright at times.
But it's not very elegant to have
two acceptable answers, so...
If it were me, I think I'd choose Rigel.